前情提要
边  缘  世  界
他们根本不知道自己惹毛了什么人
They have no idea who they just picked a fight with.
这里确实是伦敦
This is London...
但是70年以后的伦敦
...but London 70 years from what you think of as the present.
你在我们称之为“边缘”的化身之中
You're inside what we call a Peripheral.
远程临场
Telepresent.
就像使用自己身体那样操纵化身
Piloting that body as if it were your own.
我想你应该先告诉我 为什么有人来杀我和我家人
I'm thinking you should probably tell me why people are trying to come and kill me and my family.
我带你逛逛
Let me show you.
伯顿 上来 马上
Burton, get up here right now.
我看得见啦 弗林
I can see, Flynne.
-妈妈  -我能看见你了
- Mama.  - I can see you.
皮克特汽车公司
克兰顿
♪ Cut my teeth on Daddy's old LGO ♪
♪ And I lost my mind ♪
♪ Somewhere in New Mexico ♪
♪ And TW put a snake on my back... ♪
窗玻璃上有5厘米厚的聚合物
Two-inch polymer on those windows.
车门上有芳纶薄板
Kevlar plates in the door panels.
低压安全胎 热成像夜视仪
Run-flat tires. Thermal night vision.
电动门把手 车后部署了钉子和烟雾
Electrified door handles. Spike and smoke deployment from the rear.
防爆油箱
Explosive-proof gas tanks.
请在这里签名
All I need is a quick scribble right here,
这样我们交易就完成了
and we are done... and done.
科贝尔 你是要劝我们信教吗？
You go and get religion on us, Corbell?
有时候想过 图特
Yeah, sometimes, Tut,
人到了某个阶段 就会觉得自己需要改变
a man reaches a point, realizes he's got to make a change.
我是说 核心理念要改
I mean, to his core.
感觉我自己就到了这个节点
And it appears I've arrived at that frightful juncture.
知道进城路上我那些广告牌吗？
Know those billboards I got, road into town?
我都取下来了
Taking 'em down.
换上这些十字架
Putting up these crosses in their place.
我要推广一种不同性质的事业
Promoting a... a different sort of venture.
你不卖车了 我们以后的维修保养怎么办？
You stop selling cars, how do we get these serviced?
我给你终生保修 CJ
I'm gonna give you a lifetime guarantee, CJ.
你们这辈子
For the rest of your lives.
车子哪出问题
Something goes wrong?
我都免费修
I'll fix these for free.
我说话算话
You know I'm true to my word.
握手为定
Let's shake on it.
♪ I've been higher than a Georgia pine... ♪
给
Here.
上车吧 试试感觉怎么样 给 小伙子们
Hop on in. See how they feel. There you go, boys.
给 我帮你
Here. Allow me.
上车
Step right on in.
感觉不错吧？
Feels pretty good, doesn't it?
怎么样？
You good?
感受一下
See how that feels.
不能启动？
It's not working?
他在说什么？
What's he saying?
看来我们这些朋友发动不了车子啊
Well, it appears that these vehicles aren't starting up for our friends.
车窗和车门也都打不开 真倒霉
Windows and doors aren't opening either. Which is unfortunate.
在今天这种天气被反锁在车里
Locked car, day like today.
知道会热到什么程度吗？
Any idea how hot it can get?
不知道 先生
No, sir.
60摄氏度 一个小时就会丧命
Hundred and forty degrees. Takes about an hour.
我查过
I looked it up.
-放我们出来！  -要我放他们出来吗？
- Let us out!  - Should I let them out?
你知道我最喜欢美军哪一点？
You know what I love best about the U.S. military?
他们创造词汇的方式
The way they coin phrases.
当敌人的首脑指挥失误 让全军在某处集结时
When the leadership of an enemy makes the mistake of gathering in one place,
我们就向他们投炸弹
we drop a bomb on them.
-把门打开！  -这叫做“斩首行动”
- Open the door!  - Call it a... "decapitation strike."
听上去特诗意吧？
Has a real poetic ring, doesn't it?
真是活见鬼！
What the fuck?!
我猜 图特是怀疑那块玻璃不是防弹的
Tut had his doubts, I guess, about that glass being bulletproof.
来人啊 我不能呼吸了！
Come on, man, I can't fuckin' breathe!
给他们浇点水
Spray some water on 'em.
提醒他们会变得非常口渴
Remind them how thirsty they're gonna get.
你真是狗屁！
This is fuckin' bullshit, man!
王八蛋！
Come on! Let us out!
贾斯珀 如果你不能时不时地
Now, you won't get anywhere in life, Jasper,
鼓起勇气残忍一回 追求动物本能的单纯乐趣
if you don't have the courage to be cruel now and then...
你这一生不会有大出息
...just for the pure animal joy of it.
这里越来越热了！
It's hot in here!
越来越热了！
快点！
Come on!
开门！
Open it up!
该死！
Damn it!
你死定了！
You're fucking dead!
你弄完之后
Once you're done here,
把这些十字架拖过来 放在人行道上
drag those crosses over and lay 'em out on the pavement.
科贝尔叔叔？
Uncle Corbell?
我要杀了你！
I'm gonna kill you!
你要走了？
You leaving?
我会回来的 只是去拿把锤子
I'll be back. Just got to fetch a hammer.
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
边
缘
世
界
第一季     第3集
你是在泳池里撒尿吗 科贝尔？
Are you peeing in that pool, Corbell?
这是我的游泳池 不是吗？
It's my pool, ain't it?
有一天你会长大的
You'll grow up one of these days.
-然后怎么着？  -可能就只能跟你离婚了
- Then what?  - Probably have to divorce you.
至少我会有个干净的泳池
But I'll have a clean pool, at least.
我一直在考虑那笔转账
So... been thinking on that deposit.
我觉得咱们有几个选择
Way I see it, we got a few choices.
最安全的 是拒绝那笔钱
Safest route? Refuse the money.
让费舍尔兄妹活到老死
Let the Fishers live out their natural lives.
从此不再玩《老哈瓦那》
Stop visiting Old Havana.
最危险的做法
Riskiest?
拿钱 做掉费舍尔兄妹
Take the money. Kill the Fishers.
如果这是国土安全部的圈套
And if it's some sort of boneheaded Homeland Security setup,
那就一边在红洋葱州监狱度过余生
you can spend the rest of your days
一边埋怨自己愚蠢
in the Red Onion supermax, feeling like an idiot.
或者 拿钱不办事
Or... Take the money. Then do nothing.
问题是 也许这不是一个局
Problem being, maybe it isn't a sting.
我们还骗了某个不能得罪的人
And we've crossed someone who has some resources at their disposal
对方可能会用很激烈的方式
along with an inclination to solve disagreements
解决问题
in a rather vigorous manner.
我不喜欢这些方案
Can't say I'm liking any of these, hon.
没有更好的点子吗？
Sure you can't do better?
贾斯珀
Jasper.
他的老婆比利·安
His wife, Billy Ann?
是弗林·费舍尔的好闺蜜
Best friends with Flynne Fisher.
你想把这件事交给我那个傻侄子？
You really want to put something like this in the hands of our half-wit nephew?
收到的钱先别动
Let the money sit.
让贾斯珀去调查
Get Jasper to poke around.
看看费舍尔兄妹那儿有什么异常
Find out if anything unusual is happening with the Fishers,
然后再考虑怎么办
and then, revisit the matter.
《老哈瓦那》的新朋友怎么办？
And my new friend in Old Havana?
告诉他你在忙着准备 可能需要点时间
Tell him you're busy prepping. Might take a minute.
这会让我看起来很弱吧？
That makes me look weak, don't it?
狮子趴着准备突袭的时候 弱不弱？
Does a lion look weak crouching before it pounces?
天啊 弗林
Damn, Flynne.
去未来旅行
Trips to the future.
你家后面的尸体 神奇的药
Dead bodies behind your house. Magic medicine.
我的头都快爆炸了
I feel like my head's about to explode.
是呀
Yeah.
我们是在看什么？
What are we looking at, anyway?
伯顿在我手机上装的应用 让我能看见无人机
Stupid app Burton put on my phone. It lets me see the drones.
我也说不上来… 看着它们能让我安心
I don't know, I guess I... find it kind of soothing.
它们在你家上空吗？
Are they up at your house?
没有
No, ma'am.
-是的  -它们一路跟着我们到这里？
-Yeah.  -They followed us all the way here?
是莱昂一路跟着我们到这里
Leon followed us all the way here.
一定是他放上去的
He must've put 'em up.
他这样是想让我们觉得更安全？
That's supposed to make us feel safer?
他们能把你妈妈的未来说出来 就一定知道你的命运
So, if they can tell you about your mama, they must know about you, too.
或者说他们那个世界的你
Or-or their version of you?
我问了 但他们不回答
I asked them. And they stonewalled me.
不知道为什么 但我觉得不应该再问这种问题
I don't know why, but... kind of makes me start to think that I ought to stop asking.
为什么？
Because?
一定没什么好事
Must be pretty hard news, don't you think?
鉴于他们这么不想告诉我
Them not wanting to tell me this badly?
有一件事我很确定 70年后 人口少了很多
One thing I know for sure. There's a lot less people in 70 years.
很少
Whole lot.
-天哪  -是的
- Oh, shit.  - Yeah.
我知道
I know.
你真的相信 是吗？
You really believe, don't you?
是的
Yeah.
-你在干什么？  -准备装备
- What are you doing?  - Gearing up.
你在干什么？
What're you doing?
你不能在这里打印这个
You can't print this here.
他们不会允许的
They won't let you.
-谁不允许？  -永远制作打印店 伯顿
- Who?  - Forever Fab, Burton.
现在商店归我们了
Well, uh, that's us now.
我们想干嘛干嘛
So we can do whatever we want.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我们早上买下来了
We bought it this morning.
或者说是米拉格罗斯·科尔迪龙公司买了
Or Milagros Coldiron did.
我让梅肯和爱德华负责管理
I put Macon and Edward in charge.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
你得戴上那个头戴设备…
You need to be in that headset is what you need.
出去聊 马上
Outside. Now.
你让梅肯和爱德华做我老板？
You made Macon and Edward my bosses?
-他们不是你老板  -你刚才还说…
-They're not your bosses.  -You just said they were...
如果这家店是你的 他们就不是你老板 傻瓜
They can't be your bosses if you own the place, nitwit.
话说回来 你又没时间在这里工作
And you don't have time to work here anyway.
伦敦那里需要你
They need you in London.
你怎么搞得像负责人一样？
Why are you going and acting like you're in charge all of a sudden?
现在情况复杂 有很多事要处理
There's a lot of moving parts right now.
而且你需要休息
And it seemed like you needed the rest.
我们要团结一致 明白吗？
We got to be a team here, you understand that?
否则这些事都行不通
Otherwise, none of this shit's gonna work.
我同意 你手怎么了？
Agreed. What's up with your hand?
没事 就是很僵硬 我也不知道
Nothing. It's just stiff. I don't know.
把你的自行车挂上 我送你回家
Hang your bike on that. I'll drive you home.
你买了汽车？
You bought a car?
租的
It's a rental.
我马上就来
I'll be right there.
今早我从宿醉里醒来
So I woke up from a drunken stupor this morning.
你猜我找到了什么？
And guess what I found?
有个笨蛋说你可能有活给我干
Some dumbfuck said you might have a job for me?
进来吧 他们会给你配备装备
Get inside. They'll get you sorted out.
要我帮把手吗？
You want a hand?
抱歉 说错话了
Sorry, man. Wrong word.
该死 伙计
Shit, man.
你这是在伤害我的感情
You really hurt my feelings.
那就这样
Hey, there it go.
好了 过来吧 进屋
All right, fuck off then. Head on in.
大步向前走
Put your best foot forward.
你这是故意损我呢
Now you're just being an asshole.
说真的 我愿意为了这辆车断手断脚
I'm serious, dude. I'd give an arm and a leg for a rig like this.
-你太伤人了！  -这是真心话
- You cut me deep.  - I mean it.
你比我们这帮花拳绣腿有优势 毫无疑问
You got a leg up on all of us. Hands down.
这句话送给你！
This one's for you.
臭王八蛋
Motherfucker.
听着 弗林
Listen, Flynne,
我们得谈谈如果出现意外怎么应对
we need to talk contingencies. Okay?
大家要知道些什么 什么时候告诉他们
What people need to know. When they need to know it.
我告诉里斯他们 你在玩仿真游戏时
I told Reece and them that you were playing a sim.
在里面看到了一些不该看的东西
And that you saw something you weren't supposed to,
现在有人要杀你灭口
and that now somebody wants you dead for it.
我觉得这也不是瞎说 眼下先这么着
Which I guess has enough truth in it for my comfort. For now, at least.
你说呢？
You?
好的
Yeah.
正好谈谈妈妈
Which brings us to Mama.
她觉得那些药是哪来的？
Where does she think those drugs came from?
她还没问
Hasn't asked yet.
如果她拿给医生看 我们就得解释了
Well, if she shows them to her doc, we're gonna have some explaining to do.
她下次去看病 医生发现她能看见了
Yeah, I think we're gonna have a lot more explaining to do
更要非解释不可了
when she shows up to her next appointment seeing.
这事怎么说都显得太荒唐
I mean, I'd tell her the truth,
她根本不会相信 否则我就告诉她真相了
if I could find a way to make it sound halfway convincing.
你是怎么了？
You gonna share what's going on there?
我控制不了它了
I keep losing control of it.
手自己会握成拳头
It just starts squeezing without me meaning it to.
因为头戴设备的关系吗？
Headset?
有可能 但我不知道
Maybe. I don't know.
今早我都跟比利·安说了
I told Billy Ann this morning.
都跟她说什么了？
Told her what?
全都说了
Everything.
你干嘛要这么做？
Why the fuck did you do that?
回答我
Answer me.
不要用这种语气跟我说话 我又不是小孩子
Goddamn it, Burton, don't take that fucking tone with me. I'm not a child.
那你就不要像小孩那样
Then maybe you should stop fucking acting like one.
把车停下
Goddamn it, pull the car over.
-停下！  -我就是不停
-Pull it over now!  -I'm not pulling the fucking car over.
你知道吗 伯顿？
Goddamn it. You know what, Burton?
你有自己的小团队
You got your whole little posse
在你野营车外开篝火派对 我呢？
in front of that fire outside your fucking camper, but me?
比利·安是我唯一的朋友
Billy Ann is the only friend that I've got.
-好吧  -显然并不好
- Okay.  - Obviously, it ain't okay.
很显然你正在酝酿说一些屁话好惹我生气
Clearly you've got some other shit that you're brewing on that you want to say to piss me off.
你得记住 你把事情告诉比利·安
You might just want to remember that when you tell Billy Ann something,
就等于告诉了贾斯珀
you're telling Jasper, too.
我让她不要说出去
Yeah, okay. And I told her to keep it a fucking secret.
夫妻不是这样的 弗林…
That's not how it works, Flynne.
-你不能指望夫妻…  -难道你很了解...
- You can't expect a married couple...  - You don't know the first fucking thing
-夫妻和他们的相处之道？  -贾斯珀的叔叔是谁？
- about a married fucking couple and how it works.  - Who's Jasper's uncle?
操蛋
Fuck.
-他们在等你了  -行啊
- They're waiting on you.  - Great.
我还以为你会把她存放在床上
For some reason, I assumed it would be stored on a bed.
你是个浪漫的人 威尔弗
That's because you're a romantic, Wilf.
吵闹鬼没登录时 这就只是个物品
It's just a thing until our polt arrives.
不把物品放盒子里 还能放哪里呢？
And where else would you keep a thing but in a box?
阿什刚刚问我
Ash just now asked...
我有没有杀过人
...if I'd ever killed a man.
醒过来 站起来
Awake and rise.
你为什么这么命令她 列夫？
Why would she ask that, Lev?
我是在让她确信你就是找到艾丽塔的关键人物
I was simply reassuring her that you're the right person to find Aelita.
你确实也是如此
As you most certainly are.
你的过去并不丢脸 恰恰相反
There's no shame in what you did. Quite the contrary.
我的家族是盗窃组织寡头政治 所以我们招募了你
My family, the Klept oligarchy at large, it's why we took you in.
保护你
Protected you.
把你当自己人
Treated you as one of our own.
基本上是自己人
Well, almost.
你从没告诉过别人吧？
You've never told anyone, have you?
你对那些尼奥普利姆斯做过什么？
What you did to those neoprims?
连艾丽塔都没告诉？
Not even Aelita?
只有接受了那部分的你
You will never be fully yourself
你才会成为完整的自己
until you embrace that part of your soul.
去拥有那个力量
Lay claim to its power.
否则 你就跟这个化身一样空洞
Otherwise, you're just as empty as this thing.
你觉得自己就是一件物品吗？
Do you feel like a thing?
物品是没有生命的实物
A thing is an insensate material object.
严格来讲 我算是物品 但恐怕你的问题缺乏…
Technically, I qualify as such. But I'm afraid your question lacks...
欢迎回来
And welcome back.
别跟我说 我离线的时候你把我放盒子里了
Please tell me you do not keep me in a box when I'm not here.
没有！那怎么可能
No, no, no. Of course not.
我们又来厨房了
We're in the kitchen again.
如果要解释的话
Seems simple enough to me
其实很简单
when it's laid out like that.
我们绑架了玛丽尔 摘走了她的眼球
We kidnapped the Mariel woman. Stole her eyeball.
用这个眼球走进地下空间 然后被抓住了
Used that to get into the underground place. Got caught.
艾丽塔逃跑了 我也被杀了
Your Aelita woman ran away while I got myself killed.
虽然我不是侦探 但这些线索已经足够了
I'm not really a detective, but I feel like that's more than enough to get going on.
从派对开始查
Start with the party. Find out
查出玛丽尔是谁 再顺着这点往下查
who the Mariel woman is and go from there.
玛丽尔·拉斐尔
Mariel Raphael.
研究所安全部助理经理
Assistant security manager at The Research Institute.
艾丽塔也在那里工作
Which is also Aelita's place of employment.
根据逻辑可以推测你使用了她的虹膜
It would seem logical to surmise that you used her iris to gain access
进入了研究所的某个保密设施
to one of the institute's restricted facilities.
这使得接下来的一切
Which immediately makes everything that follows
都变得更加复杂
far more complex than it might otherwise be.
也更危险
More dangerous, too.
你们都害怕那个地方吗？
Y'all are afraid of that place, huh?
这么说吧 减少在研究所面前出现
Let's just say that minimizing our exposure to the RI
对我们大家都有好处
would be in our collective self-interest.
你们不是在从那里偷东西吗？
Weren't y'all stealing from it, though?
派了艾丽塔偷偷潜入我的世界
Using Aelita to sneak into my world?
“偷”这个词有点过了
Stealing seems a strong word.
“偷偷潜入”也是
Sneaking, too.
那你会怎么说？
Then, what would you call it?
你有些事情要问这位小姐姐吧？
I believe you had something you wanted to ask this young lady.
你和一个叫科贝尔·皮克特的人有什么关系？
What connection do you have to a man named Corbell Pickett?
没有关系
None.
而且我不想跟他有瓜葛 怎么了？
And I'd like to keep it that way. Why?
他是你们当地的毒品生产商 非常暴力
He's a narcotics manufacturer in your region. Quite violent.
今天早上 我们在北卡罗来纳州克兰顿发现了一起骇人听闻的案件
A grisly discovery in Clanton, North Carolina this morning.
在希尔特威尔公路上有12具尸体被订在十字架上…
Twelve bodies found hanging from crosses on Siltwell Road...
我知道科贝尔·皮克特是谁
I know who Corbell fucking Pickett is.
...都是疯狗帮联盟的成员
...reportedly members of the Mad Dogs cartel.
也知道他是什么货色 能把屏幕关了吗
What he is, too. Just turn that shit off, please.
我们一直在监控你的时间桩中的网络流量
We've been monitoring your stub's web traffic.
他的IP流量显示他突然对某样东西产生了浓厚兴趣
We've detected a considerable spike in interest from his IP address.
对什么感兴趣？
Interest in what?
你和你家人
You and your family.
我们推测是我们世界有人联系了他
Which would lead us to believe that someone from here might have contacted him.
雇他来伤害你们
In the hopes of recruiting him to harm you.
那你得把我送回去
Then you need to send me back.
马上
Now, I mean.
你们继续找艾丽塔 我一小时后回来
You keep looking for Aelita, and I'll be back in an hour.
沃尔夫冈
Wolfgang.
你接种疫苗了吗？
Uh, have they been immunized?
完全符合国家指导方针
In full compliance with state guidelines.
你多大了 亲爱的？
How old are you, darling?
再过27天我就十岁了 沃尔夫八岁
I'll be ten in 27 days. Wolf is eight.
张嘴
Open.
需要整理一下 但不严重
Needs a bit of work, but not terrible.
国家津贴应该可以报销这笔花费
The stipend from the state ought to cover such expenses.
我部门不需要慈善捐助
We won't require any charity.
国家号召我们要支持改革
We've been called upon by our country to assist with the reformation.
这是我们的责任
It's our duty to do so.
你愿意跟我们一起住到牛津郡吗？
Would you like to come and live with us in Oxfordshire?
沃尔夫能来吗？
Can Wolf come?
他们是一起被带回来的
They were reclaimed together from the streets.
两个人有羁绊
A bonded pair.
但我们只打算收养一个孩子
We were only planning to adopt one.
-嗯 那样的话…  -沃尔夫不去 我也不去
-Well, perhaps in that case we could...  -I'm not going without Wolf.
这个男孩叫沃尔夫？
Wolf is the boy's name?
沃尔夫冈的昵称
Short for Wolfgang.
DNA检测显示 他有德国和北非血统
DNA reveals German and North African heritage.
-你喜欢自己的名字吗？  -是的先生
-Do you like your name?  -Yes, sir.
但是我们要给你换个名字
But say we wanted to call you by a different name,
换个更加传统点的名字
something a little more traditional.
比如 威尔弗雷德
Like, um... Wilfred.
你觉得可以吗？
Would that be okay?
我可以叫威尔弗雷德
I can be Wilfred.
好孩子
Good boy.
玛丽玛丽很倔强
♪ Mary, Mary Quite contrary ♪
你的花园怎么样？
♪ How does your garden grow? ♪
那有银铃铛
♪ With silver bells ♪
艾丽塔
Aelita?
还有海扇壳
♪ And cockleshells ♪
漂亮女仆站成行
♪ And pretty maids all in a row ♪
玛丽玛丽很倔强
♪ Mistress Mary, quite contrary ♪
你的花园怎么样？
♪ How does your garden grow? ♪
威尔弗雷德？
Wilfred?
有银铃铛和海扇壳
♪ With silver bells and cockleshells... ♪
你好妈妈
Hello, Mum.
她上次来这是什么时候？
When was she last here?
很多年前了
It's been years.
跟你一样
Like you.
确切地说 是在你父亲去世之前
Prior to your father's death, I'm certain of that.
我还是没有原谅你
I still haven't forgiven you...
你们两个没来参加他的葬礼
you know, both of you... for not attending his funeral.
-不必非得谈这个吧？  -太丢人了
- We don't have to do this, do we?  - It was quite embarrassing.
我没指望你会道歉
Not that I'm expecting an apology.
一如既往 你问错了问题
But as usual, you're asking the wrong question
所以得不到你要的答案
and therefore, getting the wrong answer.
我猜你想问的是
What I suspect you meant to ask is,
我最后一次见到艾丽塔是什么时候？
when was the last time I saw Aelita?
-什么时候？  -一个月前
- And?  - A month ago.
可能都不到一个月
Perhaps not even quite that.
那时我在圣詹姆斯街 刚从威尔顿餐厅出来
I was in St. James's. I came out of Wiltons.
几乎跟她撞了个满怀
Practically ran right into her.
你们说话了吗？
And did you speak?
我试着跟她聊
I attempted a conversation.
但艾丽塔就那样 总是我一个人在说
But Aelita being Aelita, the effort proved to be rather one-sided.
我问她住在哪里
I asked her where she was staying.
她还是摆出那副讨人厌的
She took on that rather unattractive haughty air
傲慢神态说
that she can sometimes assume and said,
“雪最后一次在伦敦飘落的地方”
"Where snow last fell in London."
过了这么多年
After all these years,
我还是不太明白 她为何喜欢打哑谜
I can't quite understand why she needs to play at such riddles.
我露出不解的表情 她就不开心了
She grew affronted when I expressed confusion.
她说我稍微花点心思听
Said that if I'd ever bothered to pay the slightest degree of attention,
就会明白她的意思
I'd know precisely what she meant.
你是最用心听她说话的 威尔弗雷德
But you paid attention, Wilfred.
你懂她的意思吗？
And do you know what she meant?
看吧？
You see?
坐吧 威尔弗雷德 坐一会儿也行
Oh, do sit, Wilfred. Even for a moment.
你伫立在那里很令人厌烦
It's so tiresome to have you looming over me like that.
有时候我睡不着
Sometimes, when I can't sleep,
我躺在那里 想着怎么破解你和你姐姐的谜语
I lie there trying to solve the riddle of your sister and you.
我想我和你爸有些地方做得不太好
I suppose your father and I had our failings.
或者 可能我们的标准太高了
Or perhaps our standards were simply too high,
考虑到你出身的特殊性
given the particularities of your origin.
但你不能否认 我们给你提供了顶级的条件
But you can't deny we gave you the absolute top shelf of everything.
上学 机遇 一个…
Schooling. Opportunity. A...
谢谢 亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
不客气 女士
My pleasure, ma'am.
我不指望你会明白
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
说来听听
Try me.
威尔弗雷德 一个人生活
A soul grows lonely, Wilfred.
灵魂会变得孤独
Living without companionship.
普通型机器人无法满足需求？
A generic model wouldn't suffice?
是啊 我想是因为我太多愁善感了
Well, yes, yes. I suppose it is all very sentimental of me.
艾丽塔身上有些东西
But there was something about Aelita...
她有些举止和气质
something in the way she carried herself...
让我觉得非常舒服
that I always found deeply comforting.
你是指没有古怪且令人讨厌的个性吧？
Untainted by any unattractive quirks of personality, you mean?
我说了 我不指望你明白
As I said, I wouldn't expect you to understand.
她的下落 我把知道的都说了
I've said all I know about her whereabouts.
我们的茶也有点凉了
And our tea has grown unpalatably tepid.
你差不多也该上路了 你觉得呢？
So it might be time for you to be on your way, don't you think?
我会搞定皮克特
I'll take care of Pickett.
你说搞定是什么意思？
What do you mean "take care" of him?
伯顿 你可不能把科贝尔·皮克特给宰了 这太冷血了
Burton, you can't go and kill Corbell Pickett in cold blood.
你说他准备杀了我们
You said he was planning to kill us.
这样做算不上冷血
There's nothing too hot-blooded about that.
但是他才是冷血的人
But that's the kind of person that he is.
我们不是
That ain't who we are.
你知不知道
I don't know if you know this,
海军陆战队花了很多钱 把我培养成冷血动物
but the Corps actually spent a lot of money making me exactly that kind of person.
但你不在海军陆战队服役了
Come on, Burton, you're not in the Marine Corps anymore.
你知道什么叫“永远”吗？
You know what semper means?
我知道 我还知道“忠诚”是什么意思
I do. I also know what fidelis means.
我觉得你应该问自己 你忠于什么？
So I think you got to ask yourself... loyal to what?
这样吧
All right, how about this?
你给我定一个可行的计划
You find me a workable plan...
否则就用我的办法
...or we go with mine.
你做任何决定前 会先跟我商量？
You'll talk to me first? Before you make any decisions?
可以
Agreed.
说出来！
Say it.
我先跟你商量 我保证
We'll talk about it first. I promise.
糟糕
Shit.
康纳也不例外！
And that goes for Conner, too!
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我给汽车编了程序 它会以白金汉宫为中心在周边移动
I've programmed the car to move in a grid with Buckingham Palace at its center.
你要是看到任何在那晚见过的东西
If you see anything familiar from that night,
我们就能试着根据你的路线追踪到艾丽塔
we can try to trace your route back to Aelita's.
她怎么样了？
What happened to her?
我是指玛丽尔
Mariel?
她后来怎么样了？
Afterward, I mean?
装配工可以创造奇迹 我确定她没事
Assemblers can work miracles. I'm sure she's fine.
我问这个不是想让你说些好听的让我感觉好受些
I'm not asking you that so you can make me feel better, Wilf.
她似乎失踪了
She appears to have vanished.
这点装配工也可以做到
Assemblers can do that, too.
艾丽塔杀了她？
Aelita killed her?
不是艾丽塔就是研究所
Either Aelita or the RI.
他们不喜欢安全漏洞
They don't take fondly to security lapses there, I'm afraid.
那时我以为是在玩仿真游戏
I thought I was playing a sim.
是啊 事实是 如果你刺伤我们
Yes, well. It turns out if you prick us,
我们就会流血
we bleed.
等等 倒回去
Wait, go back.
我记得我们在这里转弯了
I think we turned there.
我也记不清了
I don't know.
我们下去走走怎么样？说不定会想起什么
Why don't we take a walk for a bit then? See if anything jumps out.
你走那边 我走这边
You go that way. I'll go here.
我们可以连线 这样你也能看到我的视野
We can link up so you can see what I'm seeing.
-连线？  -你会听到铃声
- Link up?  - You'll hear a ringing.
听到后就这样滑动 然后食指点击拇指
When you do, swipe, tap your thumb and forefinger.
正在校准
连接已建立
天啊
Holy shit.
共享设置为全感官 不仅仅是视觉和听觉
It's set to full sensory. Not just visual and aural.
可能需要一点时间来适应
So it might take a moment to acclimate.
该死 我觉得不舒服
Ah, fuck, I feel sick.
是的 估计是我的宿醉造成的 你可以校准一下 这样
Ah, yes. My hangover, I imagine. You should be able to calibrate it here.
好点吗？
Better?
是的
Yeah.
这是我最奇怪的经历了
This is the weirdest fucking thing I've ever felt.
感觉就像你中有我一样
I mean, it's like I'm... I'm part of you?
你能明白我意思吗？
Does that make sense?
连线是双向的吗？
Does it work both ways?
我给你什么感觉？
What do I feel like?
什么？
What?
你像纯洁而喜悦的独角兽 费舍尔女士
You're all rainbows and unicorns, Ms. Fisher.
去你的
Fuck off.
而且有布鲁斯情调的背景音乐
With a bluesy sort of soundtrack underneath.
重低音
Heavy bass.
你可以这样来调节你我的连接程度
Up or down. To pull me in or out.
吉米酒吧
贾斯珀
Jasper.
我觉得我早该和皮克特先生聊聊了
I think Mr. Pickett and I are overdue for a discussion.
有什么需要帮忙的？
How can I be of assistance?
我有一杯敬酒和一杯罚酒 皮克特先生
I've got a carrot and I've got a stick, Mr. Pickett.
咱们先说说敬酒吧？
You want the carrot first?
把我和我妹做掉 他们会给你多少钱？
How much did they promise for you to make me and my sister dead?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
前几天这个价码是九百万美元
Going rate a few nights ago was nine million dollars.
如果他们给的价码比这少
So if they told you any less than that...
显然说明他们对你的期望值不高
...they obviously don't think too highly of you.
你摊上什么事了？
What're you mixed up in?
我保证不会侵犯你的业务范围
Nothing that'll encroach on your line of business, I promise.
但我可以每周给你二十万美元 你要确保不伤害我们
But I can offer you 200 grand a week just to leave us the fuck alone.
我们握手成交怎么样？
So, why don't we shake on it
然后我就走人
and I'll be on my way.
我想再听听罚酒是什么
I'm curious about the stick.
-你知道这是什么？  -有所耳闻
- You know what these are?  - Heard about them.
具体是什么？
What, exactly?
这玩意会留下的创伤和持久影响
How they messed you up pretty good.
感谢你为国家做出的无私奉献
And I thank you for your service.
我跟你讲个故事吧
Can I tell you a story?
海军陆战队在农村城镇里招募军人 并植入神经控制装置
The Corps targets rural towns for haptic recruitment.
一起长大的孩子具有现成的小队作战凝聚力
Kids who grew up together offer ready-made small-unit cohesion.
插入神经控制装置之后就得到了统一化的肌体组织
Plug the haptics in and you got a unified organism.
速度 强度 动作勇猛度
Speed, intensity, violence of action.
老实说 如果我杀红了眼
Honestly, when it got hot enough,
我都不知道自己在干什么
generally, I wasn't even aware of what I was doing.
就像个杀人机器 你懂我意思
Like a hand wouldn't be, if you get my meaning.
战争结束后我去到匡提科 走进一家酒吧
Anyway, when the war was over, I was at Quantico. Walked into a bar.
看见一个人坐在凳子上
Saw a guy sitting on a stool...
我突然啥都不知道了
...and I just blacked out.
失去了意识
Gone.
我清醒过来之后 发现那人躺在我脚下
When I came to, I was standing over that guy.
原来我已经把他打得只剩半口气
Found that I'd beaten him 'bout a half inch shy of death.
我之前甚至都没见过他
I'd never even seen him before.
但是我队里的一名中士
But a sergeant in my unit...
他16岁的时候被那家伙欺负过
he'd gotten jumped by that motherfucker when he was 16 years old.
因为神经控制装置 我就有了记忆
And because of the haptics, I had that in me.
也有了不知为何只想毁了那个王八蛋的
Along with a visceral imperative to destroy that son of a bitch,
本能冲动
without even knowing why.
这故事真不错
That is quite a tale.
但我没听出这个故事
But if there's a moral in it,
想说明什么道理
I believe I missed it.
如果我和我妹妹受到什么伤害 并且是你在背后搞事情
If anything happens to me or my sister, and you're behind it,
那你可得提防着点 因为我不是一个人
you ought to have your affairs in order. 'Cause I'm not just me now.
千千万万战友会为我讨回公道
I'm all the men I served with.
这就是你最厉害的罚酒？
That's your best stick?
你觉得这里安全吗 皮克特先生？
You feel safe here, Mr. Pickett?
你太年轻了 也许记不得
You're too young to remember, maybe.
但这个小镇曾经一团糟
But this town was a real shithole once.
由一帮最卑鄙的无赖管理
Run by the lowest sort of trash.
是我改变了局面
I changed that.
差不多就在一夜之间
Pretty much overnight.
让这里重新成为宜居之地
Made it a nice place to live again.
干净 安静
Clean, quiet.
我的小镇
My town.
是的
So, yeah.
我确实觉得这里很安全
Yeah, I guess I do feel pretty safe here.
下一枪就会打穿你的耳朵
The next one's in your fucking ear.
这就是我的罚酒
That's my fucking stick.
每周二十万怎么样？
Two hundred a week sound good?
谢谢你 伙计
Appreciate it, man.
恐高吗？
Acrophobic?
不怎么恐高
Not particularly.
很好
Good.
跟我走走 我要呼吸一下新鲜空气
Walk with me. I need some air.
研究所总部是我们最早的一批空气洗涤器
The R.I. Headquarters was the first of our air scrubbers.
你加入我们之前很久就建成了 你知道它们的工作原理吗？
Built long before you joined us. Do you know how they work?
-只知道大概  -说来听听
-Only in the broader sense.  -Tell me.
它们从大气中捕获碳
They capture carbon from the atmosphere.
除此之外 还要说具体的技术？
But beyond that, the specific technology?
就好像问我鸟是怎么飞起来一样
It would be like asking me how a bird flies.
你花了太长时间了
You're taking too much time.
我们承受不起
We can't afford it.
-时间桩…  -是的
- The stub...  - Yes. Yes, yes, yes, yes.
这是一个独特的挑战 我很清楚
It presents unique challenges. I'm well aware.
也许你搞得太复杂了
Maybe you have too many moving parts.
雇佣兵团队 坚不可摧的小镇联盟
Teams of mercenaries. Impenetrable small-town alliances.
应该有更简单的办法来结果这个女孩 不是吗？
It seems there ought to be a simpler way to kill a girl, doesn't it?
就一个人？用合适的武器？
Just one person. With the appropriate weapon?
我们当下有什么问题呢？
And what about our problems in the here and now?
似乎艾丽塔·韦斯特跟格蕾丝·霍加特是校友
It appears that Aelita West went to school with Grace Hogart.
她们做了一年的室友
They were roommates for a year.
很令人苦恼
Well, that's distressing.
我一直很喜欢格蕾丝
I've always been quite fond of Grace.
如果你觉得有必要 我可以解决这事
I can address it, if you'd like.
我自己会处理
No. I will.
你找到艾丽塔的资金来源了吗？
Have you discovered the source of Aelita's funding?
我们还在努力调查
We're still struggling to untangle that.
不过你是对的 感觉是盗窃组织
You were right, though. There's a Klept feel to it.
具体是哪个家庭还不清楚 但如果要我猜的话….
Which specific family remains murky, but if I had to guess...
我不希望你去猜 丹尼尔
I don't want you to guess, Daniel.
我需要确切的答案
I want you to find out for certain.
然后告诉我干掉了多少人
And then I want a body count.
你应该特别清楚 我只要挥挥手
I'm sure you're aware that I could easily eliminate you.
就有很多方法可以弄死你
In any number of ways, with the simple wave of my hand.
但我很重视你 丹尼尔
But... I value you, Daniel.
我不希望你只是出于恐惧才为研究所效力
And I wouldn't want you serving the needs of the Institute simply out of fear,
恐惧带来的激励效果是最小的
which is the weakest type of motivation.
而且时效也短
Powerful only in the short term.
博士！
Doctor!
它们拍打着翅膀
They flap their wings.
-什么？  -鸟呀
- Ma'am?  - Birds.
鸟就是这样飞的
That's how they fly.
亲一个 丹尼尔 把事情办好
Kiss, kiss, Daniel. Get it done.
艾丽塔说十年后我就不在了
Aelita says I'm likely not to exist in ten years.
她这话什么意思？
What'd she mean by that?
喂？在吗？
Hello? You there?
威尔弗？
Wilf?
我们找到艾丽塔后 你可以问她 因为我不知道
When we find Aelita, you can ask her because I have no idea.
她叫我“小鬼” 这是什么意思？
She called me a polt. What's that mean?
“吵闹鬼”的简称
Short for poltergeist.
我们都是这样称呼时间桩来的人
That's how we refer to people from the stub.
就像鬼一样 看似在这里 实际并不在
Like a ghost. Here but not here.
你是指完美的帮凶吧
Perfect accomplice, you mean.
说到帮凶 我是不是该担心那个警察？
Speaking of which, is there any reason I should be worried about the police?
在拐角右转
Turn right at the corner.
慢慢走 我会从另一个方向过来
Walk in an unhurried manner. I'll approach from the opposite direction.
怎么了？
Yes?
弗林的化身已经注册了吧
Please tell me the Peripheral is registered.
是的
It is.
但有一些不受欢迎的增强功能
With a few frowned-upon augmentations.
我跟她下车之前你怎么不说？
Okay, right, and you couldn't tell me that before I stepped out with it?
出什么问题了？
What's the problem?
我跟她分头行动 扩大搜索范围 现在有个伦敦警察在跟踪她
We separated to cover more ground. Now a Met koid is following her.
快去找她
Well, catch up to her,
别让她跟那玩意儿说话
and for Christ's sake, don't let her talk to the damn thing.
如果那警察发现弗林来自时间桩 我可救不了你
If the Met finds out Flynne is from the stub, you're on your own.
我们会移除所有连接
We'll scrub all connection.
不过我会寄爱心包裹去韦克菲尔德监狱给你
I'll be sure to post a care package to you in Wakefield prison, though.
老天 阿什
For fuck's sake, Ash.
我可以现在就送她回家
I could just send her home now.
不 这样会引起怀疑 听我指示
No, it'll look dodgy. Just wait for my prompt.
我等着
I'll be listening.
配合我
Follow my lead.
你看见我摸下巴时 就问我你能不能回家
And when you see me touch my chin, ask if you can go home.
有什么可以帮忙吗？
May we be of assistance, Constable?
这个化身在附近移动的方式
This Peripheral has been moving about the neighborhood
违反了多项算法预测
in a manner that violates algorithmic predictions, by several degrees of certainty.
我是被派来调查的
I was dispatched to investigate.
你的身份 先生
Identity, sir?
-威尔弗·内瑟顿  -确认
- Wilf Netherton.  - Confirmed.
这位是雷尼·波蒂斯的化身
And this is Rainey Portis, in the Peripheral.
雷尼是加拿大公民
A citizen of Canada.
如果你查一下 应该会看到
If you check, I think you'll see
我以她的名义申请了远程访问签证 总共十次
I applied for a remote-visit visa in her name. Ten trips.
已经用了两次 这是第三次
Two of which have been used. This being the third.
你们没有申请过第三次访问 也没有任何批准
A third visit was neither requested nor approved.
雷尼是临时想来访问的
Well, Rainey was feeling spontaneous.
你的远程访问被撤销
Your remote visit is revoked.
请交出化身以供检查 然后…
Please surrender the Peripheral immediately for inspection and deconstruction.
你想知道我们为什么从车里出来 是不是？
You'll be wondering why we exited the vehicle, I suppose.
我们吵架了
Bit of an argument, actually.
如果你不介意 我想听听你的意见
I'd really value your opinion, if you wouldn't mind.
在雷尼前两次访问中
On Rainey's first two visits,
她说这个化身跟她本人不是很像
she mentioned how the Peripheral didn't look much like her.
她要我下次另外租一个化身
Wanted me to rent a different model next time she came to London.
但她不知道这个化身不是租的
But... what she didn't know is the peri isn't a rental.
这是我的
I own it.
是根据我前女友打造的
It was modeled on an ex-girlfriend.
我觉得还是继续用着比较省事
And it seemed easier to just keep using it
这是我偷懒了 做错了
which was lazy of me and wrong
雷尼这次过来时发现还是同样的化身就生气了
because when Rainey arrived this time and found herself in the same peri, she grew angry.
她说我这样轻率地忽略她的要求 就是不够尊重她
Said I must not respect her if I ignored her requests so cavalierly.
然后她跳出汽车 所以发生了现在这事
She jumped out of the car. Which led us here to this present moment.
但是 警官 问题是这样的
But here's the thing, Constable.
我开始对这位女士有了感情
I believe I'm starting to have feelings for this woman.
至少有了感情的苗头 如果你明白我的意思
Or at least I'm feeling the possibility of feelings, if you follow my drift.
我觉得你非常迷人
I find you extremely alluring.
冰雪聪明
Intelligent.
耐人寻味
Intriguing.
勇于冒险
Intrepid.
你难道看不出来吗？
Can't you fucking see that?
我能回家了吗 警官？
May I go home now, Constable?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
请你尽快为她的访问注册 内瑟顿先生
I'd advise you to register her visit as soon as possible, Mr. Netherton.
当然 警官
Yes, of course, Constable.
再会
Good day.
跟我来
Follow me.
努兰博士？
Dr. Nuland?
格蕾丝
Grace.
谢谢你这么快就赶过来了
Thank you for popping by on such short notice.
应该的
Of course.
总感觉我们没什么机会好好聊天 是吗？
Feels like... we never really have much of a chance to chat, do we?
是我怠慢你了
Feels like a dereliction on my part.
我们都知道你特别忙
Well, we all know how terribly busy you are.
-你最喜欢哪个地方？  -什么？
-Do you have a favorite spot?  -Ma'am?
你最爱去哪个地方充电？我喜欢来这里
A place you go to, to revive your spirits? This is mine.
-是这里的美景让你神清气爽吗？  -是蜜蜂
-It's the view that nourishes you?  -The bees.
我是说它们的无知
Their ignorance, I mean.
我觉得这很有警示意义 让我精神一振
I find it cautionary, in a bracing way.
他们孜孜不倦地采花酿蜜
They go about their business so assiduously
却没有意识到自己有多脆弱
without any awareness of how vulnerable they are.
就算周围的东西都会杀死它们 但它们还是照样在那
All the things that killed them off in the first place, they're still out there.
我们尽了最大努力 让它们远离危险
We do our best to keep them at bay, of course.
但只要稍一放松警惕 一连串危机就会接踵而至
But one momentary lapse in vigilance, and a whole cascade of crisis descends.
你知道吗 在过去五千年里
Do you know they've had two extinction events,
蜜蜂发生了两次灭绝
just in the past five years?
然后 你知道...
And then, well, you know...
然后又是从无到有 渐渐发展
that long climb back up from nothingness.
它们遇到你真幸运
Well, they're lucky they have you.
其实人类和它们没两样
We're no different, really. People.
我们看着这一切 想象着末日
We look out on all this and we imagine that the Jackpot,
和当时所有的恐怖事件都已成为过去
with all its horrors, is safely buried in the past.
但是投入的人力… 那些心血
But the labor involved to keep it so. The care...
你会是第一个明白的 是吧？
You'd be the first to understand, though, wouldn't you?
这就是你现在工作的重点
That's the whole point of the work you're doing.
你从时间桩带来的信息总有一天会把人类
The data you're bringing back from the stub may save us all one day.
从自己手中拯救出来
From ourselves.
很荣幸能够尽绵薄之力 博士
I'm honored to be in a position to help, Doctor.
你有很多朋友吗 格蕾丝？
Do you have many friends, Grace?
有一些
Some.
艾丽塔·韦斯特 算一个吗？
Aelita West. Does she count as one?
应该算 那时我们一起寄宿在学校
I suppose. We boarded together in school.
你知道她曾经受雇于我们的生物多样性部门
Then you're aware she was employed in our Biodiversity Department.
曾经？
Was?
你觉得一个在生物多样性部门的人
How do you suppose someone in Grains and Legumes
怎么会知道我们时间桩研究部的？
might become aware of our Stub Research Division?
她很好奇 所以我…
She was curious, so I...
我没有跟她分享实际内容 博士
It's not as if I shared anything of substance, Doctor.
我绝不会…
I-I would never...
在末日之前有个国家叫巴拉圭
There was a country called Paraguay once, before the Jackpot.
你知道吗？
Do you know it?
不知道
No.
那里的人有个说法
People there had a saying.
如果你很想分享一个秘密…
If you feel compelled to share a secret,
我是说 非常重要 意义重大的秘密
I mean, a really important secret... an existentially important one...
你应该先把坟挖好
then you should dig a grave first.
-给谁挖？  -是挖了给谁 亲爱的
-For who?  -For whom, dear.
要不就是听到秘密的那个人
Either for the person you're telling...
要不就是你
...or for yourself.
我很抱歉 博士 我理解 我让你失望了
I'm so sorry, Doctor. I've let you down. I can see that.
茶里下了药
There's a chemical in the tea.
你的身体在消化它时
As your body processes it,
你的汗水会模仿大黄蜂释放的信息素
your sweat begins to mimic a pheromone hornets release.
搞得那些小不点有点激动起来了
It's gotten our little friends a tad agitated, I'm afraid.
你知道是你让我别无选择吧？
You understand, don't you? How you've left me no choice?
我有两个小孩
I have two small children.
对啊！没错！
That's it. Exactly.
想想他们！
Think of them.
想想你会如何努力去保护他们
Think of the lengths you'd go to, to protect them.
努兰博士 求求你！
Dr. Nuland, please.
别这样 我求求你了！
Please. Please don't, I beg you.
求求你 别这样 做什么我都愿意！
Please. Please don't. I'll do anything.
问你个问题？
Ask you a question?
使用小便池的时候
Using a urinal,
尿到正确的地方有多难？
how hard is it to get the pee in the right spot?
我指的尿对地方 就是别尿在地上
And by right spot, I mean anywhere but the floor.
不是我尿的
It ain't me doing it.
或许你可以让你的朋友们也别尿在地上 养成好习惯
Well, I mean, you could get your friends to stop, too. Start a trend.
如果你想 我可以试试
I could try, if you want, but...
不过凭良心说 女人要做到这点确实容易很多 你们是坐着尿的
to be fair, women do have it easier. Sitting down and all.
开个玩笑
Which was a joke.
-开个玩笑  -非常好笑
- It was a joke.  - Mm-hmm. Super funny, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
到家了 贾斯珀 可以把卡车熄火了
This is home, Jasper. Time to shut off the truck.
我得去叔叔那里送点东西
I got to drop something at my uncle's.
什么东西？
What?
不知道 就是一个包
I don't know. It's a bag.
-希望里面没有毒品  -没有
- Better not be any drugs in there.  - There ain't.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为我叔叔知道你不喜欢毒品
'Cause my uncle understands how you feel about that.
是我从永远制作打印店拿来的
Also, it's from Forever Fab.
-是弗林给你的？  -梅肯和爱德华给的
-Flynne gave it to you?  -Macon and Edward.
比利·安 别这样
Billy Ann... don't.
如果你帮我个忙 我就去做晚饭
I'll get dinner started if you do me a favor.
去查查这事的来龙去脉
Find out what this is about.
-要怎么查？  -你自己想
- How am I supposed to do that?  - Figure it out.
我也没问你要怎么做晚饭吧？
I'm not asking you how to get dinner going, am I?
你可千万别动那钱 贾斯珀·贝克
And don't even think about taking any of that, Jasper Baker.
天哪 比利·安 我又不傻
Jesus, Billy Ann. I'm not an idiot.
好的
Okay.
♪ High heel lady spitting at the Nickajacks ♪
♪ Businessman with a needle and a spoon ♪
♪ Coyote chewing on a cigarette ♪
♪ Pack o' young boys going howlin' at the moon ♪
♪ Hey, darlin' ♪
♪ Sleeping on the blacktop ♪
♪ Running through the trees, honey ♪
♪ Hey, darlin' ♪
♪ Leaving for the next town ♪
♪ Less'n my sense catches up with me ♪
嘿
Hey.
给
Here you go.
遇到什么麻烦吗？
Any trouble with that?
没有 我告诉他们我要什么 然后他们就交给我了
No, sir. I told them what I was after, and they handed it over.
-看过包里的东西吗？  -没有
-Have a peek inside?  -No.
你知道我不会干那种事
You know I wouldn't feel right doing that, Uncle Corbell.
不过 我大概可以猜到里面是什么
I mean, I can kind of tell what's in it. I think. Just by the feel.
你猜是什么？
And what's your guess?
钱
Money.
是费舍尔兄妹给的
From the Fisher family.
-你邻居 是吧？  -是的
-Neighbors of yours, aren't they?  -Yeah.
你觉得很吃惊吗？他们付了我二十万美金
You, uh, find it at all surprising? Them paying me 200 grand?
说实话 有点吃惊
Little bit, I'll be honest, yeah.
如果我告诉你 他们还会继续付 每周一次
What if I told you they were planning to keep doing it, once a week
以后都这样 你会怎么想？
for the foreseeable future?
我会想知道他们哪来这么多钱
I don't know, I suppose I'd wonder where all the money was coming from.
你是聪明的年轻人 贾斯珀
You are a smart young man, Jasper.
这个问题确实很关键
For that is indeed the million dollar question.
-你要一叠吗？  -不 这怎么好意思…
-You want one?  -No, I wouldn't, uh...
我是说…
I mean...
没事 拿一叠
Go ahead, take it.
-拿着  -好的
- Go ahead.  - All right.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要给你上一堂宝贵的人生经验课
Now, I'm gonna offer you a valuable life lesson here.
如果别人给你钱
Before you accept any cash from someone,
接受之前 你得先问问别人想要你干什么
always ask what they might want in exchange.
不 太晚了
No, no, no, no. Too late.
你已经拿了
You've taken it.
你想要…
What do you, uh...
你想要我干什么？
What do you want in exchange?
我想要你找出这个关键问题的答案
For you to find the answer to that million dollar question.
-你的意思是…  -老实跟你说吧
-You mean, like...  -Look, tell you straight up.
我有点担心费舍尔兄妹
I'm a little concerned about the Fishers.
我觉得他们摊上的事有点大
I think they've gotten themselves involved in something that's maybe
他们自己有点摆不平
a tad bigger than they can handle.
你还记得疯狗帮吗？
You remember the Mad Dogs?
就是类似于那样的恶势力
That's the sort of wickedness we're talking about.
又回到我们小镇了
Coming back to our town.
我知道的越多 我就越能帮着费舍尔兄妹预防不测
Now, the more I know, the more I can watch out for the Fishers.
-因为他们都是好人  -是的
-'Cause, uh, they seem like nice folks.  -They are.
你不希望他们有什么不测 是吗？
So you wouldn't want anything bad to happen to them... would you?
好…
Well.
就这样
Right.
好的
Okay.
在你连接
Hey, what's it feel like
神经装置的时候 是什么感觉？
when you link up with your haptics?
很难描述
It's hard to describe.
为什么问这个？
Why you asking?
我也连接了一次
Well, I think I did it.
觉得跟你这个类似 跟威尔弗连接的
Or I guess something similar to it. With Wilf.
你知道吗？
You know?
你现在最好要小心
You better be careful, now.
怎么了？
Why?
需要经过培训才能处理合并模式
It takes training to handle a merge.
否则人会迷失在里面
Folks can get lost in it.
怎么迷失？
Lost how?
两个灵魂合而为一
Well, two souls coming together as one
如果你不把自己捋顺 你会有恋爱的感觉
can kind of feel a lot like love, if you don't know any better.
他们叫它“神经漂移”
Haptic drift, that's what they call it.
哦
Right.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
这不是真的吧？
It ain't real, is it?
不是真的
No, I'm afraid.
艾丽塔留下了一个谜语 或许这是找到她的线索
Aelita left a clue as to her potential whereabouts. A riddle.
她总是很喜欢猜谜
She was always fond of riddles.
我刚才在试图揣摩她的心思
I was trying to get into her frame of mind.
线索是什么？
What was it? The clue.
“雪最后一次在伦敦飘落的地方”
"Where snow last fell in London."
我妈妈的梳妆台上有幅画 上面写着
My mother had a painting over her bureau. It said, um...
“黑斯廷斯战役 哈罗德国王倒下的地方”
"Battle of the Abbey. The Spot Where Harold Fell."
“斯诺”可能不是指雪
You don't think that... I mean, Snow could be a person,
而是人名？
do you?
约翰·斯诺
John Snow.
那是谁？
Who's that?
艾丽塔景仰的一个智者
One of Aelita's intellectual heroes.
一位英国医生 他发现了霍乱是如何传播的
An English doctor. He discovered how cholera spread.
约翰·斯诺是在哪里去世的？
Where did John Snow die?
1858年6月16日 在伦敦
In London. On June 16, 1858.
具体地址？
Where precisely?
萨克维尔街18号
18 Sackville Street.
我们走 去斯诺在伦敦去世的地方
Let's go. To where Snow last fell in London.
我到了
I've arrived.
有人比我们早了一步
Someone got here before us.
我们家也有一台
We have one of those back at home.
一模一样吗？
The exact same?
是啊 我们家那台也坏了
Yeah. Ours is broken, too.
我父亲去世后钟就停了
It stopped after my dad died.
你家的钟指向几点？
What time is your clock set to?
2点15分
2:15.
做得很好
Well done.
他们怎么了？
What happened to them?
都是化身
Peripherals.
被遗弃了 好多天没充电
Abandoned for days without a nutrient bath.
阿什和奥西恩可以通过这些连接追踪到他们的本体
Ash and Ossian should be able to trace the connections back to their operators.
什么？
What?
伯顿
Burton.
这是什么？
What is it?
是植入物
It's an implant.
艾丽塔的？
Aelita's?
她一定是遇到袭击之后取下来的 避免被追踪
She must have removed it after the attack so she couldn't be traced.
我们该走了
We should go.
欢迎回来 费舍尔女士
Welcome back, Ms. Fisher.
你是威尔弗雷德·内瑟顿吧？
And Wilfred Netherton, is it?
还记得这个吗？
Remember this?
我猜你在想 “杀了我 然后游戏就结束了”吧？
I assume you're thinking, "Kill me, then game over," right?
但我可以告诉你 创伤是会留下痕迹的
But I assure you, the trauma leaves a mark.
有点痛 是吧？
Hurts a little, don't it?
你要我做什么？
What do you want with me? Huh?
回答我
Answer me!
除非你死 不然她不会罢手
She won't stop. Not till you're dead.
你只是在苟延残喘
You're only delaying the inevitable.
延长痛苦罢了
Drawing out the pain.
你拿了一些东西
You took something.
什么东西？
What?
下集预告
边  缘  世  界
我想要回去 伯顿
I wanna go back, Burton.
我担心你没有想清楚
I'm worried you're not thinking clearly.
下一波追杀我们的人还有多久会找上门？
How long do you think it's gonna be till someone else comes around wanting to kill us?
我直说 你老是这样溜走 显得你不值得信任
Your constant slipping away is as if you couldn't be trusted.
所以这就是我的世界将会发生的事？
So this is what's coming in my world.